John Trever Cartoons
John Trever Cartoons
1977-2010
Trever, John
23 linear ft. (50 oversize boxes)
American editorial cartoonist for the Albuquerque Journal. Collection contains original artwork for more than a thousand cartoons, convering subjects such as the O.J. Simpson Trial, the Iran/Contra affair, the Oklahoma City bombing, the Branch Davidian incident in Waco, the 1992 and 1996 presidential elections, the presidencies of Bill Clinton and George H. W. Bush, all areas of U.S. domestic and foreign policy, current issues of the day (e.g., the deficit, Congressional gridlock, etc.), and many other events and personalities.
3961698
Biographical History
John Trever is an American editorial and political cartoonist. A graduate of Syracuse University, he was the political cartoonist for the Albuquerque Journal for 35 years, from 1976 to 2011. He has been honored for his work by the Society of Professional Journalists, the Free Press Association, the Overseas Press Club, the New Mexico Legislature and the Albuquerque Arts Alliance, and his cartoons are distributed to more than 350 daily papers by King Features Syndicate.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The John Trever Cartoons consists of original artwork for more than a thousand editorial cartoons, dating from 1985 to 1996. Subjects covered include the O.J. Simpson Trial, the Iran/Contra affair, the Oklahoma City bombing, the Branch Davidian incident in Waco, the 1992 and 1996 presidential elections, the presidencies of Bill Clinton and George H. W. Bush, U.S. domestic and foreign policy, current issues of the day, and many other events and personalities. In a few cases Trever has annotated an item on the back, indicating the subject.
There are gaps in the collection -- that is, not every single date is represented. In some cases the original was sold or given away, or retained by the donor. For some, but not all, of these missing items, photocopies (annotated by Trever as to date and the disposition of the original) were provided with the original donation. A complete list of dates present in the collection is available in PDF form. In two cases, a cartoon is in the form of a negative transparency rather than original art
Arrangement of the Collection
Chronological, as identified by donor.
Related Material
has the collections of more than 200 cartoonists. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Other Related Finding Aids
A complete list of dates present in the collection is available in PDF form.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Cartoonists; Bush, George, 1924- -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Clinton, Bill, 1946- -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Trever, John.; United States. -- Congress -- Caricatures and cartoons.; American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Cartoonists -- New Mexico.; Editorial cartoons -- United States.; Elections -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Taxes -- Caricatures and cartoons.; World politics -- 1985-1995 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; World politics -- 1995-2005 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; United States -- Foreign relations -- Caricatures and cartoons.; United States -- Politics and government -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Artwork.; Cartoons (humorous images); Drawings (visual works); Editorial cartoons.; Cartoonists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of John Trever, 2003, 2012-2015.
Inventory
- Cartoons
  The following is a list of inclusive dates for each box in the collection. A complete list of dates present in the collection is available in PDF form.
  - Cartoons, 1976, Nov-Dec; For all of 1976: 16 original items, 4 photocopies (Oversize 18)
  - Cartoons, 1977, Jan-Jun; For all of 1977: 112 original items, 34 photocopies (Oversize 18)
  - Cartoons, 1977, Jul-Dec; For all of 1977: 112 original items, 34 photocopies (Oversize 19)
  - Cartoons, 1978, Jan; For all of 1978: 127 original items, 25 photocopies (Oversize 19)
  - Cartoons, 1978, Feb-Jul; For all of 1978: 127 original items, 25 photocopies (Oversize 20)
  - Cartoons, 1978, Aug-Dec; For all of 1978: 127 original items, 25 photocopies (Oversize 21)
  - Cartoons, 1979, Jan; For all of 1979: 122 original items, 27 photocopies (Oversize 21)
  - Cartoons, 1979, Feb-Jul; For all of 1979: 122 original items, 27 photocopies (Oversize 22)
  - Cartoons, 1979, Aug-Dec; For all of 1979: 122 original items, 27 photocopies (Oversize 23)
  - Cartoons, 1980, Jan; For all of 1980: 144 original items, 21 photocopies (Oversize 23)
  - Cartoons, 1980, Feb-Jul; For all of 1980: 144 original items, 21 photocopies (Oversize 24)
  - Cartoons, 1980, Aug-Dec; For all of 1980: 144 original items, 21 photocopies (Oversize 25)
  - Cartoons, 1981, Jan-Jun; For all of 1981: 158 original items, 23 photocopies (Oversize 26)
  - Cartoons, 1981, Jul-Dec; For all of 1981: 158 original items, 23 photocopies (Oversize 27)
  - Cartoons, 1982, Jan-Aug; For all of 1982: 143 original items, 22 photocopies (Oversize 28)
  - Cartoons, 1982, Sep-Dec; For all of 1982: 143 original items, 22 photocopies (Oversize 29)
  - Cartoons, 1983, Jan-Mar; For all of 1983: 143 original items, 22 photocopies (Oversize 29)
  - Cartoons, 1983, Apr-Oct; For all of 1983: 143 original items, 22 photocopies (Oversize 30)
  - Cartoons, 1983, Nov-Dec; For all of 1983: 143 original items, 22 photocopies (Oversize 31)
  - Cartoons, 1984, Jan-May; For all of 1984: 149 original items, 13 photocopies (Oversize 31)
  - Cartoons, 1984, Jun-Dec; For all of 1984: 149 original items, 13 photocopies (Oversize 32)
  - Cartoons, 1985, Jan-Sep; 108 original items, 12 photocopies (Oversize 10)
  - Cartoons, 1985, Oct-Dec; 32 original items, 6 photocopies (Oversize 11)
  - Cartoons, 1986, Jan-Jun; 70 original items, 8 photocopies (Oversize 11)
  - Cartoons, 1986, Jul-Dec; 70 original items, 7 photocopies (Oversize 12)
  - Cartoons, 1987, Jan-Apr; 45 original items, 5 photocopies (Oversize 12)
  - Cartoons, 1987, May-Dec; 102 original items, 10 photocopies (Oversize 13)
  - Cartoons, 1988, Jan-Sep; 108 original items, 7 photocopies (Oversize 14)
  - Cartoons, 1988, Oct-Dec; 31 original items, 6 photocopies (Oversize 15)
  - Cartoons, 1989, Jan-Aug; 89 original items, 3 photocopies (Oversize 15)
  - Cartoons, 1989, Sep-Dec; 46 original items, 7 photocopies (Oversize 16)
  - Cartoons, 1990, Jan-Mar; 40 original items, 3 photocopies (Oversize 16)
  - Cartoons, 1990, Apr-Dec; 107 original items, 12 photocopies (Oversize 17)
  - Cartoons, 1991 Jan-Aug; 101 original items, 9 photocopies (Oversize 1)
  - Cartoons, 1991 Sep-Dec; 40 original items, 6 photocopies (Oversize 2)
  - Cartoons, 1992 Jan-Apr; 50 original items, 4 photocopies (Oversize 2)
  - Cartoons, 1992 May-Dec; 107 original items, 4 photocopies (Oversize 3)
  - Cartoons, 1993 Jan-May; 57 original items, 5 photocopies (Oversize 4)
  - Cartoons, 1993 Jun-Dec; 71 original items, 13 photocopies (Oversize 5)
  - Cartoons, 1994 Jan-Aug; 81 original items, 12 photocopies (Oversize 6)
  - Cartoons, 1994 Sep-Dec; 39 original items, 5 photocopies (Oversize 7)
  - Cartoons, 1995 Jan-Apr; 35 original items, 4 photocopies (Oversize 7)
  - Cartoons, 1995 May-Dec; 74 original items, 8 photocopies (Oversize 8)
  - Cartoons, 1996; 106 original items, 24 photocopies (Oversize 9)
  - Cartoons, 1997, Jan-Oct; For all of 1997: 101 original items, 7 photocopies (Oversize 33)
  - Cartoons, 1997, Nov-Dec; For all of 1997: 101 original items, 7 photocopies (Oversize 34)
  - Cartoons, 1998, Jan-Aug; For all of 1998: 104 original items, 25 photocopies (Oversize 34)
  - Cartoons, 1998, Sep-Dec; For all of 1998: 104 original items, 25 photocopies (Oversize 35)
  - Cartoons, 1999, Jan-Jul; For all of 1999: 93 original items, 11 photocopies (Oversize 35)
  - Cartoons, 1999, Aug-Dec; For all of 1999: 93 original items, 11 photocopies (Oversize 36)
  - Cartoons, 2000, Jan-Aug; For all of 2000: 109 original items, 5 photocopies (Oversize 36)
  - Cartoons, 2000, Sep-Dec; For all of 2000: 109 original items, 5 photocopies (Oversize 37)
  - Cartoons, 2001, Jan-May; For all of 2001: 117 original items, 11 photocopies (Oversize 37)
  - Cartoons, 2001, Jun-Dec; For all of 2001: 117 original items, 11 photocopies (Oversize 38)
  - Cartoons, 2002, Jan-Mar; For all of 2002: 120 original items, 7 photocopies (Oversize 38)
  - Cartoons, 2002, Apr-Dec; For all of 2002: 120 original items, 7 photocopies (Oversize 39)
  - Cartoons, 2003, Jan-Sep; For all of 2003: 114 original items, 9 photocopies (Oversize 40)
  - Cartoons, 2003, Oct-Dec; For all of 2003: 114 original items, 9 photocopies (Oversize 41)
  - Cartoons, 2004, Jan-Jun; For all of 2004: 122 original items, 17 photocopies (Oversize 41)
  - Cartoons, 2004, Jul-Dec; For all of 2004: 122 original items, 17 photocopies (Oversize 42)
  - Cartoons, 2005, Jan-Mar; For all of 2005: 112 original items, 10 photocopies (Oversize 42)
  - Cartoons, 2005, Apr-Dec; For all of 2005: 112 original items, 10 photocopies (Oversize 43)
  - Cartoons, 2006, Jan-Sep; For all of 2006: 102 original items, 8 photocopies (Oversize 44)
  - Cartoons, 2006, Oct-Dec; For all of 2006: 102 original items, 8 photocopies (Oversize 45)
  - Cartoons, 2007, Jan-Apr; For all of 2007: 110 original items, 1 photocopies (Oversize 45)
  - Cartoons, 2007, May-Oct; For all of 2007: 110 original items, 1 photocopies (Oversize 46)
  - Cartoons, 2007, Nov-Dec; For all of 2007: 110 original items, 1 photocopies (Oversize 47)
  - Cartoons, 2008, Jan-May; For all of 2008: 129 original items, 7 photocopies (Oversize 47)
  - Cartoons, 2008, Jun-Dec; For all of 2008: 129 original items, 7 photocopies (Oversize 48)
  - Cartoons, 2009, Jan-Feb; For all of 2009: 108 original items, 6 photocopies (Oversize 48)
  - Cartoons, 2009, Mar-Dec; For all of 2009: 108 original items, 6 photocopies (Oversize 49)
  - Cartoons, 2010, Jan-Feb; For all of 2010: 116 original items, 2 photocopies (Oversize 49)
  - Cartoons, 2010, Mar-Dec; For all of 2010: 116 original items, 2 photocopies (Oversize 50)